<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>implementation on SDN-Cloudstack - Documentation</title><link>/en/tags/implementation/</link><description>Recent content in implementation on SDN-Cloudstack - Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/tags/implementation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Software Backbone</title><link>/en/rapport/content/project_implementations/software_backbone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/en/rapport/content/project_implementations/software_backbone/</guid><description>Containerization One of the principles we wanted to implement in our project is to containerize our applications. Containerization is a technique that consists in encapsulating applications in independent and isolated units. This allows a fast deployment, and more security. It allows us greater modularity, since the installation that was once hard, and that impacted the system environment, is no longer necessary. To deploy an application, you only need one command, or a block in a YAML file.</description></item><item><title>Colaboration tools</title><link>/en/rapport/content/project_implementations/colaboration_tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/en/rapport/content/project_implementations/colaboration_tools/</guid><description>This section is dedicated to the collaboration tools we used during the realization of our project.
Hugo Hugo is a static website generator, based on Markdown files. We used it throughout this project to create a documentation for the project. This way, we had in text, all the technical information about the project, which allowed us not to have to depend continuously on the other team member to understand and use the work done.</description></item><item><title>Evaluation</title><link>/en/rapport/content/project_implementations/evaluation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/en/rapport/content/project_implementations/evaluation/</guid><description>This section is devoted to our objective and subjective evaluation of the project.
Objective evaluation In relation to the specifications During this project, we were able to develop a very large majority (\approx 80%) of what was requested in the specification. We have therefore created a system of device configuration by SNMP. We also developed a user interface with management of pre-saved configurations, on-the-fly configuration and display of information on the devices.</description></item></channel></rss>