<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Report on SDN-Cloudstack - Documentation</title><link>/rapport/</link><description>Recent content in Report on SDN-Cloudstack - Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>fr-fr</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 17:07:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/rapport/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Summary</title><link>/rapport/resume/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/rapport/resume/</guid><description>Summary In this report, we will explore the creation of a communication interface for the network devices of the IUT&amp;rsquo;s classrooms. This interface will be a way to create or modify a network infrastructure dynamically, according to the needs of the professor. We will talk about the context behind the project, i.e. the infrastructure already in place, the needs that led us to conduct this project and the possible solutions explored.</description></item><item><title>Aknowledgements</title><link>/rapport/thanks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/rapport/thanks/</guid><description>To begin this project report, we would like to thank our technical tutor Mr. HUSSENET Laurent for his support and help throughout the project. A big thanks also to our tutor Ms. GOBILLARD Delphine who helped us organize and prepare the different tests. We thank more generally all the teaching staff who supported us throughout this project. Finally, we thank Alexandre GOSSARD and Corentin FREIRE, with whom we helped each other in the realization of our respective projects.</description></item><item><title>Table of Content</title><link>/rapport/content_table/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/rapport/content_table/</guid><description>Introduction
General Idea Context Exceptations of the project Application functional dividing What is a topologie Web portal Topologie manager Topologie database Project realisation Web portail Software interface settings Database Topologie manager Project implementation Software backbone Colaboration tools Evalution Conclusion</description></item><item><title>Index</title><link>/rapport/word_index/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/rapport/word_index/</guid><description>ACCESS The access mode is a port configuration mode on Cisco equipment that is used for connecting devices (computer, printer &amp;hellip;).
API API means Application Programming Interface, an API is in fact a service that exposes configuration and data retrieval procedures, through configurable URLs.
CI/CD CI/CD stands for continuous integration / continuous deployment. It is a process that allows to automatically publish on a server the progress of a project when it is considered acceptable.</description></item></channel></rss>