<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AFD on SDN-Cloudstack - Documentation</title><link>/tags/afd/</link><description>Recent content in AFD on SDN-Cloudstack - Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>fr-fr</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/afd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is a Topology</title><link>/rapport/content/application_functional_dividing/what_is_a_topo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/rapport/content/application_functional_dividing/what_is_a_topo/</guid><description>The entire project is based on the ability to easily deploy various topologies on network devices. So we will see what a topology is and how to define them.
A topology is a configuration file that we can deploy on the switches. This file will contain the configuration of the different interfaces in a format defined beforehand (JSON, YAML &amp;hellip;).
The configuration itself, specifies the interface configurations (trunk, access or disabled), there is also information on the various VLANs (names and numbers).</description></item><item><title>web portal</title><link>/rapport/content/application_functional_dividing/web_portal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/rapport/content/application_functional_dividing/web_portal/</guid><description>The web portal is the visible part of the project, it is our user interface. Being in contact with the user, our interface must be easy to access and easy to use.
The access to the interface will be done in several ways to make it as accessible as possible. The first way is via its URL (www.sdn.chalons.univ-reims.fr). The second way is by using a QR Code placed in the different classrooms so the user will just have to scan the code to get to the web interface where the user will have to identify himself before choosing the topology he wants to deploy.</description></item><item><title>Topology Manager</title><link>/rapport/content/application_functional_dividing/topologie_manageur/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/rapport/content/application_functional_dividing/topologie_manageur/</guid><description>The topology manager is the key part of our project, it is the software part that makes the link between the web portal, the assets and the database. We will see concretely how it works and why we need it.
Today, changing a configuration is done manually using protocols that require human intervention (port console, ssh, telnet), however this generates a human dependency. Even though these methods allow you to change configurations, it requires the intervention of a authorized person.</description></item><item><title>Topologie database</title><link>/rapport/content/application_functional_dividing/topologie_database/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:35:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>/rapport/content/application_functional_dividing/topologie_database/</guid><description>The database is the memory of our project. It is the tool that will allow us to store all the different topologies, but also to retrieve them when necessary. The topology files can look like this:
{ &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Vlan1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;description&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Vlan1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;port_id&amp;#34;: 1, &amp;#34;status&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;up&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;operstatus&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;up&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;vlan&amp;#34;: null, &amp;#34;speed&amp;#34;: 1000000000 }, { &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Vlan10&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;description&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Vlan10&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;port_id&amp;#34;: 10, &amp;#34;status&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;up&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;operstatus&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;up&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;vlan&amp;#34;: null, &amp;#34;speed&amp;#34;: 1000000000 }, { &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;StackPort1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;description&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;StackPort1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;port_id&amp;#34;: 5179, &amp;#34;status&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;up&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;operstatus&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;up&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;vlan&amp;#34;: null, &amp;#34;speed&amp;#34;: 0 } (see Appendix 5)</description></item></channel></rss>