<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>API on SDN-Cloudstack - Documentation</title><link>/technique/api/</link><description>Recent content in API on SDN-Cloudstack - Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>fr-fr</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:59:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/technique/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Api Url List</title><link>/technique/api/api_url_list/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 12:42:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/technique/api/api_url_list/</guid><description>Liste of fonction needed for the API and the corresponding URL.
GET General Section Action URL get running config /api/v1/running-config Vlan Section Action URL get all vlan list /api/v1/vlan/all get specific vlan info by id /api/v1/vlan/{vlan_id} get specific vlan info by name /api/v1/vlan/{vlan_name} get specific vlan interface member by id /api/v1/vlan/{vlan_id}/interface get specific vlan interface member by name /api/v1/vlan/{vlan_name}/interface Interface Section Action URL get all interface list /api/v1/interface/all get inerface neighbor /api/v1/interface/neighbor get specific interface info by id /api/v1/interface/{interface_id} get all interface @IP /api/v1/interface/all/ip get specific interface @IP /api/v1/interface/{interface_id}/ip get all interface status /api/v1/interface/all/status get specific interface status /api/v1/interface/{interface_id}/status Switch Section Action URL get specific switch property /api/v1/switch/{switch_id} get the vlan list of a specific switch /api/v1/switch/{switch_id}/vlan SET General Section Action URL set new running config /api/v1/running-config/{config_id} Vlan Section Action URL Interface Section Action URL set all interface mode /api/v1/interface/all/{mode} set specific interface mode /api/v1/interface/{interface_id}/{mode} set all interface to vlan /api/v1/interface/all/{vlan_id} set specific interface to vlan /api/v1/interface/{interface_id}/{vlan_id}</description></item><item><title>SNMP/API link</title><link>/technique/api/link_snmp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 12:42:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/technique/api/link_snmp/</guid><description>To communicate with the assets, the API uses the SNMP protocol. You can find more information about the protocol on the dedicated research page. This article discusses the use of this protocol with the API.
Basic libraries: Initially, to design our API, we used PySNMP. It is a high level library entirely made with Python allowing to use the SNMP protocol with the Python language.
It is possible to do any SNMP action with this library, however, it has several drawbacks:</description></item></channel></rss>